icici lombard general insurance is
one of the leading private sector
non-life insurers in india that offers
a comprehensive and well diversified
range of products
the company is showing consistently a
positive result quarter on quarter
here never look back presents the q2
results of icici lombard general
insurance 2020.
let's get into the video
[Music]
the company has started in 2001. it's a
joint venture between icici bank
that's india's second largest bank and
fairfax financial
holdings limited a financial services
company that is based in toronto icici
bank had 64 percent stake and
fairfax had 36 percent in the joint
venture
the company has tied up with karuvaisha
bank in 2019 for selling bank assurance
products
in august 2020 icici lombard
acquired bharathi axa general insurance
through
a share swap deal
the company's market capital is rupees
167 crores price to earning ratio is
41.1
return on capital employed is 28.7
current stock price is rupees 1258
book value is 154 written on equity
is 20.9
highest stock price is rupees 1440 and
the lowest stock price
is rupees 805
[Music]
the non-life insurer has released its q2
earnings yesterday
the company has declared a jump of 35
percent in net profit
that is rupees 415.74 crores in the q2
of 2020. while the q2 of 2019
it has posted rupees 307.91 crores
the total income has gone up to rupees
two thousand eight eighty three point
four crores
from rupees two thousand seven thirteen
nine point six seven crores
the last year the investors believe that
the company is consistently showing a
positive performance
quarter on quarter
here's the company's what analysis the
strength is
the company is virtually debt free it
has been maintaining a healthy dividend
payout
of 18.81 the weakness is
promoter holding has decreased over the
last three years
that is to minus four point zero three
percent
opportunity is brokers upgraded
recommendation
or target price in the past three months
the threat is stocks are with high
profit to earn english
[Music]
let's compare it with its peer hdfc life
insurance
this quarter icici lombard has done a
better performance in net profit
compared to htfc life insurance refer
the table for
detailed information
[Music]
here is the detailed three years
quarterly results comparison
sales of the company is consistently
increasing in the last three years
operating profit has seen a hike from
rupees
457 crores the last year two rupees 542
crores this year
in september 2018 it was rupees 436
crores net profit of q2 2018 was rupees
crores in the last year q2 it was rupees
308 crores and at present
it is rupees 415.74
crores
the shareholder pattern goes like this
the promoters hold 51.89
the foreign institutional investors hold
27.1 percent
the domestic institutional investors
hold 13.59 percent and the public holds
7.4
since last three years the promoters and
public shares
have decreased foreign institutional
investors and domestic institutional
investors share
have increased gradually
the investors are being bearish on the
company's stocks
for quite some time now we'll have to
wait and see
what bank the q2 earnings will do from
monday
what do you all think is it going to be
bullish or continue to be bearish
do let us know your thoughts in the
comment section
we hope the video was informative do
consider to subscribe to our channel
a like for the video would surely going
to motivate us to bring more informative
videos
we'll be right back soon until then stay
tuned